haven't seen the fires and the
temperature extremes and the climate
extremes that are becoming more and more
prevalent on the planet and they will
get worse there is a way that we can
draw down carbon there is a way that we
can act saluto genic lee and that we
come out of this period of chaotic
upheaval that has dissolved structures
that no longer serve and will dissolve
more of these structures that no longer
serve and that we will come together and
find saluto genic ways to build new
structures that will actually be driving
the emergence of health on all scales
this is my great hope and it's
definitely rekindled after this
wonderful visit by Anthony Capone and do
check out his website do check out The
Lancet report yes there's always room
for improvement
wording there's still an element of
talking only about the utilitarian value
of health to humanity instead of
speaking about the intrinsic value of
individual community and planetary
health for all species for all of life
so I think we still have a long way to
go but it seems like we're beginning to
gain momentum and part of that might
just also be that we need to put energy
behind this concept of planetary health
that I did some early explorations on in
2004 5 and 6 and of course I can't say
this leave it like that without naming
elders people like Patrick Geddes like
Ian McHarg Robert Costanza has done a
lot of work on the importance of health
as as a planetary
condition so I'm not saying with my idea
in the slightest I'm just saying it's
really nice that somebody mentioned to
me that what I did in tunneling into all
this
in the early 2000s was actually
pioneering work and that it hasn't ended
up getting lost on a shelf in the
University of Dundee library but that it
has slowly made its way out there
and influenced key people that will
influence policy and hopefully will
actually make a difference so end of
this rather long video diary I hope that
because it wasn't windy and it was a
lovely day here we just saw the
cathedral and is a wonderful seafront of
Palmer and I hope it was clear enough
that you understood all this and please
comment please send links and let's
begin to feed this saluto genic health
generating vision and the framework of
planetary health into the wider process
of the regeneration rising regeneration
rising
trim tabs unite let's make this century
the century of Earth regeneration for
the benefit of the earth and her people